Chris Harley

Software Engineer Atlanta, GA | (678) 865-3314

Portfolio | Github | Linkedin | Email

Creative software engineer with a passion for learning and the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. I'm a U.S Army Veteran with a background in operations. Combined with my military and management experience I bring strong skills in problem solving and team cohesion.

Software Development Skills

 Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, Redux, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Flexbox, CSS Grid, AWS, HTML, CSS, ES6, Mongo Db, API, Git, Agile, CRUD Applications, Remote Development

Education

Berklee College of Music | B.A. Music Business | Boston, MA

Dec 2011 - Dec 2015

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

March 2020 - July 2020

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Software Development Portfolio

soundWav Live Site | Github

June 2020

- Member of a 2-person development team building an full stack recording studio booking application
- Primary responsibility included building a PostgreSQL database allowing users to create an account, and successfully book time in a recording studio
- Built with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, EJS, Sequelize

top3 Live Site | Github

May 2020

- Member of a 2-person development team building a travel application that list the top three restaurants, hotels, tours, nightlife and site seeing for the entered location
- Responsibilities included designing and assembling a fully mobile-responsive layout and fetching data from a third party API
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Triposo API

scenelt Live Site | Github

April 2020

- Front end project to view movie posters. You can add movies to your watch list to view later and see what movies you have watched. This projects acts as your personal keeper of what movies you've seen and also is great to check out movie posters
- This project use the OMDb movie API
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OMDb API

Professional Work Experience

DevelopATL | Freelance Web Developer | Atlanta, GA

May 2018 - Present

- Design, build and maintain web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Confer with customers to prioritize needs, resolve conflicts and determine solutions
- Maintain understanding of current web technologies through continuing education

Luxottica | Distribution Supervisor | Atlanta, GA

July 2017 - March 2018

- Carried out supervisory responsibilities in accordance with company policy
- Responsible for interviewing, hiring, and training employees
- Developed tracking system that double worked production efficiency

Phillips-Van Heusen | Operations Assistant | Atlanta, GA

January 2016 - July 2017

- Monitored associates to ensure timely and quality of production
- Developed organization system to increase department production
- Provided training and guidance to subordinate personnel

Division Operations Training & Planning Manager | U.S Army

June 2005 - October 2015

- Responsible for all training operations of over 400 personnel
- Ensured all personnel met department of defense training regulations
- Served as liaisons between units and senior officers to ensure mission readiness